what's up everybody Phil Blackman for
baraban.com we got a fun one for you
today we interviewed Simon Miller a pro
wrestler who also knows his way around
the gym we're going to talk about what
makes this incredibly jacked individual
that jacked how he manages his diet how
he manages his training and how he does
it all while traveling along the road in
the world of professional wrestling if
you want to learn anything about how
athletes train and prep themselves for
competition or for whatever physical
Endeavors they're doing in the leadup to
them and how they do it while on the
road just go to google.com typee in
barbend training and all of our training
content will come up and it'll give you
a glimpse inside the world of these
Elite athletes what does it take to be a
pro wrestler with a jacked physique and
a following of 324,000 YouTube
subscribers well Simon Miller is that
guy barbin caught up with Miller WS he
is on tour with the last match of pro
wrestling Rock experience portraying the
show's lead heel which is a villain
within the world of pro wrestling down
the east coast of the us we learned how
Miller trains and diets we got some
sample workouts so you can see how he
trains while he's in the G him on the
road and everything you need to build a
physique worthy of the squared Circle
let's get into it when asked about his
current training split and how he
prefers to work out from week to week
while on the road Simon Miller said for
years I focused on traditional
bodybuilding workout splits like back
and biceps chest and triceps and so on
currently he's doing a pushpull leg
split he finds that grouping body parts
into three distinct workouts makes it
easier to see progress in the gym he
makes sure to hit each muscle group
twice per week but otherwise it's simple
math if you train once per week that's
52 sessions a year if you double it
you're at 104 workouts and we agree at
barbend that Miller is bang on here
training a muscle group twice weekly to
reap the maximum hypertrophy benefits
Push Pull legs can be a tricky workout
split though because you only get one
day off per week assuming that you run
all of your workouts on back-to-back
days Simon said I always listen to my
body and take an extra day off if needed
the best piece of Fitness advice I have
ever received was to listen to how your
body feels your body knows what it needs
in addition to his training split Miller
also tries to get at least 30 minutes of
fasted cardio in per day then there's no
need to do it fasted he says but he says
that it's not only a great way to start
his day he just has a coffee he goes to
get something done before the Suns come
up and it feel makes him feel as though
he is ready to take on whatever that day
presents to him forward when asked about
walking us through one of his workouts
that he does on his push bow split days
Miller said his push workout starts with
a shoulder exercise though he always
tries to warm up before any strength
training he performs 10 minutes on a
stair climber 10 minutes of dynamic
stretching and then he'll do ramp up
sets until he gets into his first
working set now his ramp up set looks
like this 10 reps with a lightweight
eight reps with a slightly heavier
weight four reps with a moderate weight
three reps with a mildly challenging
weight and then he'll do a rep at his
working weight to test the waters to see
how his body feels before attacking his
working sets one thing that's
interesting about Miller's training is
that he no longer does compound
exercises he's found that once you build
your base of strength the compound
exercises in his opinion lose the
relevance ever since he started
wrestling he's mostly stuck to isol
ation movements to limmit the stress on
his joints he's found that he can still
progress as long as he incorporates
Progressive overload because in the
world of training it's really about
improving yourself there is no
competition other than you in the gym
the science behind it also backs Miller
up Progressive overload is the Bedrock
of any successful resistance training
program especially when it comes to
trying to increase strength when asked
about what Simon Miller's biggest level
up for him was in the gym he said quote
honestly the biggest shift has been
realizing how awful squats are I used to
squat heavy because I thought that's how
squat should be done it's nonsense I
stripped the bar down and started again
prioritizing my form adding 5 kg each
session not only did I see better
results despite lifting less weight but
after a few months I was back to my
quote Old strength because my form had
improved still you can't take it easy on
legs they hold you up every day and we
at barbend agree that he is correct
studies on training to failure tend to
show that you can gain muscle even if
you aren't taking yourself to the brink
of failure every set training with
greater intensity can make your workouts
more efficient since you don't generally
need to do as many sets to get a
comparable stimulus Miller continued
saying quote I think most people throw
weights around as soon as you get out of
that mindset and recognize that form and
range of motion need to come first the
difference in progress you'll see is
night and day now shifting over to how
Miller diets in order to maintain all of
this training he said quote my diet is
as basic as it gets it's Protein Plus
smart carbohydrate and fat choices
Miller does count calories when he is
looking to either bulk up or or lose fat
but he's been in a maintenance stage for
his physique for some time now so he's
lost track of the exact numbers at the
time of the interview however he does
have a personal trainer who does remind
him on a need to know basis if his
calories are getting out of hand when
barbin asked if there are any specific
go-tos for food or specific foods that
Miller avoids he said quote I believe in
high calorie and low calorie days
depending on what my training looks like
overall my diet is relatively old school
for breakfast I'll have oatmeal with
protein powder mixed in then chicken and
rice later on a bagel with nut butter
and another protein shake in the
evenings I rely on rice porridge protein
powder and occasionally some cereal as a
small treat it stops me from craving
sweets throughout the week I try to keep
my sugar intake to a minimum but we
aren't robots there has to be some
enjoyment in your diet otherwise what's
the point depending on how I feel I'll
squeeze in a cheat meal once every week
or two no one has the brain power to
always stick to a strict diet it's just
not realistic the key is to get back on
the wagon as fast as possible one off
meal isn't going to ruin everything
knowing that Miller is in the
professional wrestling world where
travel is abundant we asked him about
strategies he uses to stick to his diet
while on the road and asked if he meal
preps he said quote eating well on the
road is the hardest part of any diet
I'll rely on meal prep for about a week
but after that you've got to make smart
choices I'll go for grilled chicken
breast and white rice if I can find it
ultimately even if I fall out of my
routine I'll fall back into it just as
quickly when I get home there's no point
in getting overly worked up about it I
try to get five or six meals daily
that's mostly to ensure I eat enough of
the relevant food groups if you want to
wait until the evening to get your Mac
grows in why not dieting isn't a one
shoe fits all activity while I'm on the
road I prioritize protein and hope the
rest takes care of itself what happens
on any given day isn't important it's
all about the long game so there you
have it that's what a superjack pro
wrestler like Simon Miller who's also
the star of ups and downs of what
culture wrestling YouTube phenomenon
says about how to maintain a physique
and diet on the road if you want to
learn anything more about Simon Miller's
diet and training you can just head over
to Google type in Barb and Simon Miller
and his piece his interview will come up
we look forward to you checking that out
for yourself as well but until then I'm
Phil blechman for Barb ben.com thanks
for watching
[Music]